Guide to the Records of the American Defense Society 1915-1942 (bulk 1918-1920; 1935-1939) MS 14
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Printed Material, 1915-1942
  - Subseries 2. Printed Material: Outside Sources
    From 1924 to 1929, topics include crime and criminology, congressional bills, eugenics, fascism, communism in Mexico, socialism, Soviet Union, Bolshevism, religion, and politics (LaFollette, Al Smith). Periodicals include numerous copies of the Congressional Record, The American Standard, and newsletters from the Better America Federation of California.
    Material from 1930 to 1942 concerns Soviet Union/Soviet recognition, communism, Judaism, the New Deal, FDR, banking, investments, the economy, Mexico, socialism, elections, the Supreme Court, traffic accidents, immigration, Japan, world events and the war in Europe, and democracy. Periodicals include The Patriot, The Awakener, Moscow News, Free Press, The Fellowship Forum, National Republic, and the "Kiplinger Washington Letter." There are numerous newsletters from Robert Edmondson regarding Judaism, Jews in the US, Bolshevism, and a libel case against him (1934-1937), with titles such as "Capitalist-Jews Backing Communists?".
    Also included in this subseries are several posters, most regarding labor, and sedition. Ephemera includes programs, invitations, and tickets for various organizations' events; also advertisements for publications.
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1915-1917 Sept. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1917 Oct.-Dec. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1918 Jan.-June (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1918 July-Sept. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1918 Oct. 1-14 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1918 Oct. 15-Nov. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1918 Dec., [1918] (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1919 Jan.-Sept. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1919 Oct.-Dec. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, Posters, 1919 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, National Security League Handbook, 1919 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1920 Jan.-Mar. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1920 May-Dec. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1922 Jan.-Apr. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1922 May-Dec. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, [1922] (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, [1920-1922] (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1923 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, Posters, 1920-1923 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1924 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1926 Jan.-June (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1926 July-Oct. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1926 Nov.-Dec. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1927-1929 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1930-1932 Apr. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1932 May-1933 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1934 Jan.-Aug. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1934 May (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1934 Sept.-Oct. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1934 Nov. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1934 Dec. (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, An Ultramodern Oligarchic Manifesto, 1934 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1935 Jan.-Mar. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1935 Apr.-May 14 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1935 May 15-June (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1935 July-Sept. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1935 Oct.-Dec. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, [1935] (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1936 Jan. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1936 Feb. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1936 Mar. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1936 Apr. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1936 May-July (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1936 Aug.-Dec. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, [1936] (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1937 Jan.-Apr. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1937 May-Oct. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1937 Nov.-Dec. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, [1937] (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1938 Jan.-Apr. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1938 May-July (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1938 Aug.-Oct. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1938 Nov.-Dec.; 1938 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, [1938] (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, [1936-1938] (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1939 Jan.-Feb. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1939 Mar.-June (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1939 July-Dec. (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, [1930-1939] (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1940 Jan.-June (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1940 July-Dec. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, 1941-1942 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, [1938-1942] (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, Posters, 1939-1940 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, Ephemera, 1918-1928 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Printed Material: Outside Sources, Ephemera, 1935-1939, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Series IV. Newspaper Clippings, 1917-1938, undated
  This series contains mostly newspaper clippings collected by ADS. Clippings concern topics of interest to the society, as well as ADS activities. Also included in this series are a few complete editions of daily newspapers.
  Clippings are arranged by year. Those that were previously attached to correspondence or memorandums are filed separately. Please note that many of these clippings are brittle.
  - Newspaper Clippings, Clippings Copied, 1917-1919 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Clippings Copied, 1920-1940 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Clippings Moved, 1918-1927 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1917-1918 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1918 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1918 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1918 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1919 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1919 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1919 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1920 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1921-1928 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1932-1935 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1936-1941 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Newspapers, 1918-1920 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Newspapers, 1921-1938 (Box 22, Folder 4)